Guide to the Thomas Hilliard Papers 1937-1967
University of Chicago Library
Hilliard, Thomas. Papers
1937-1967
.5 linear feet (1 box)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Thomas Hilliard, saxophone, clarinet, and flute teacher. The Thomas Hilliard Papers contain printed music and jazz pedagogical instruction books.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Thomas Hilliard taught saxophone, clarinet, and flute in Chicago, IL. Hilliard graduated from DePaul University and was involved in name bands and acts, records, jingles, suburban jazz festivals, and broadcasts featured on ABC, CBS, NBC, and WGN.
Scope Note
The Thomas Hilliard Papers contain printed jazz and blues music by various publishers. There is a series of jazz pedagogical instruction books by Maury Deutsch.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Hilliard, Thomas; Deutsch, Maury; Feather, Leonard G.; Porter, Cole, 1891-1964; Arrangements (Popular music and jazz); Blues (Music); Jazz; Popular music; University of Chicago. Chicago Jazz Archive
INVENTORY
- Arranging, Book I, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Arranging, Book II, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Arranging, Book III, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Art of Expression, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Dictionary of Chords, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Instrumentation and Voice Leading, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Orchestration: Ensembles, Counterpoint, Polyharmony, Form, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- System of Vocal Scoring, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Theory of Psychological Associations, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Voicing by Acoustics, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Pedagogical Fingering Chart, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Printed Music, "Blues Book" Leeds Music, Jack Tracy, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Printed Music, "Bugs" Bower's Bop Duets, Charles Colin, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Printed Music, Cole Porter Song Album, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Printed Music, Jazz: An Exciting Story of Jazz Today, Leonard Feather, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Printed Music, Jazz Conception for Saxophone Duets, Lennie Niehaus, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Printed Music, Jazz-Cool Sounds Plus Exciting Progressions, Hal McKusick, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Printed Music, Rodgers and Hart Songs,1937 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Printed Music, Studies in Jazz Performance, John Mehegan, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Printed Music, The 33 by BVC (Bregman, Vocco, and Conn), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)